<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashruidan Site</title>
    <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ashruidan Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:20:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ashruidan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 05 - The Repetition Rule</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-05---the-repetition-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:20:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-05---the-repetition-rule/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical game of Go, every move leads to a new and unique position. However, there is a special scenario where the game could fall into an endless cycle of repeated moves. To prevent this, the &lt;strong&gt;Repetition Rule&lt;/strong&gt; ensures that no position can be repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preventing-infinite-loops&#34;&gt;Preventing Infinite Loops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain situations, such as the one shown below, a player can capture a stone, only for the opponent to recapture it on the next turn, creating a loop. This would result in an endless game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 04 - The Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-04---the-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:22:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-04---the-life-and-death/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve learned how to capture, how to read sequences, and how to make life by creating two eyes. Now it’s time to delve deeper into the concept of &lt;strong&gt;life and death&lt;/strong&gt; and discover how identifying the &lt;strong&gt;vital point&lt;/strong&gt; of a group can help you save your stones or kill your opponent’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-life-and-death&#34;&gt;What is Life and Death?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, &lt;strong&gt;life and death&lt;/strong&gt; refers to whether a group of stones can survive or be captured. A group is considered alive if it can secure two eyes, while a group without sufficient space to make two eyes is doomed to die. It is critical to recognize the status of your group to get the initiative and play first the vital point to get the control into the life and death of your groups or opponent&amp;rsquo;s groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 03 - The Suicide Rule</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-03---the-suicide-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 09:44:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-03---the-suicide-rule/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Suicide Rule&lt;/strong&gt; prevents self-capturing moves and has implications for &lt;strong&gt;life and death&lt;/strong&gt; on the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-capture-as-illegal-moves&#34;&gt;Self capture as illegal Moves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, a player cannot place a stone on an empty intersection completely surrounded by their opponent&amp;rsquo;s stones. Such a move would leave the stone with no liberties and is considered illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ashruidan.github.io/images/day03_illegal.png&#34; alt=&#34;day03_illegal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is an exception: if the surrounding opponent&amp;rsquo;s stones are also completely surrounded by your stones, the move is allowed. This is because, in capturing the opponent&amp;rsquo;s stones, your stone regains its liberties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 02 - The Reading Skill</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-02---the-reading-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:36:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-02---the-reading-skill/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter, we explored the &lt;strong&gt;Rule of Capture&lt;/strong&gt;, learning how liberties affect the capture of stones. However, not all captures are immediately obvious. In some situations, even if you try to save a stone, the opponent can force it into atari repeatedly until it’s ultimately captured. This is where the importance of &lt;strong&gt;reading&lt;/strong&gt; begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-reading-&#34;&gt;What is Reading ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt; is the ability to visualize sequences of moves in advance. It’s a fundamental skill in Go, enabling players to foresee outcomes and make informed decisions. For example, if a capture is unavoidable, a player can choose to play elsewhere to minimize losses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 01 - The Rule of Capture</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-01---the-rule-of-capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 04:20:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-01---the-rule-of-capture/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;strong&gt;Advent of Go&lt;/strong&gt;, a 25 chapters long guide where each day is built upon the concepts of the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will not delve into the history or variations of Go, instead it will help you acquire the necessary knowledge and skills to perceive the depth of this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, Go is a two-player turn-based game where one player uses black stones and the other uses white. Black always plays first. On each turn, players can either place a stone on an empty intersection of the board or pass their turn. Once placed, a stone cannot be moved. However, stones can be removed through &lt;strong&gt;capture&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
