<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashruidan Site</title>
    <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ashruidan Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:36:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ashruidan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 02 - The Reading Skill</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-02---the-reading-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:36:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-02---the-reading-skill/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter, we explored the &lt;strong&gt;Rule of Capture&lt;/strong&gt;, learning how liberties affect the capture of stones. However, not all captures are immediately obvious. In some situations, even if you try to save a stone, the opponent can force it into atari repeatedly until it’s ultimately captured. This is where the importance of &lt;strong&gt;reading&lt;/strong&gt; begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-reading-&#34;&gt;What is Reading ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt; is the ability to visualize sequences of moves in advance. It’s a fundamental skill in Go, enabling players to foresee outcomes and make informed decisions. For example, if a capture is unavoidable, a player can choose to play elsewhere to minimize losses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 01 - The Rule of Capture</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-01---the-rule-of-capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 04:20:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-01---the-rule-of-capture/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;strong&gt;Advent of Go&lt;/strong&gt;, a 25 chapters long guide where each day is built upon the concepts of the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will not delve into the history or variations of Go, instead it will help you acquire the necessary knowledge and skills to perceive the depth of this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, Go is a two-player turn-based game where one player uses black stones and the other uses white. Black always plays first. On each turn, players can either place a stone on an empty intersection of the board or pass their turn. Once placed, a stone cannot be moved. However, stones can be removed through &lt;strong&gt;capture&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
