<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ashruidan Site</title>
    <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ashruidan Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:20:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 23 - The Review</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-23---the-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:20:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-23---the-review/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, reviewing games is one of the most effective ways to improve. Whether analyzing your own games or studying professional matches, reviews allow you to uncover mistakes, learn new strategies, and refine your judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reviewing-your-own-games&#34;&gt;Reviewing Your Own Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-review is a vital tool for personal improvement. After each game, take time to reflect on your decisions and understand what went right and what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most effective way to learn from a review is to play serious games with sufficient thinking time, but at a pace that keeps the game&amp;rsquo;s objectives in focus. Set specific goals to concentrate on during the game, which can later serve as a framework for reviewing your performance. Focus on critical moments, missed opportunities, mistakes, and an overall evaluation of the game to gauge how well you achieved your objectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 22 - The Style</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-22---the-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:35:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-22---the-style/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, your style is the personal touch you bring to the game. It reflects your preferences, strengths, and approach to solving problems on the board. At lower levels, you might not be able to discern your style. Only with experience and exposure to different ways of playing will you start noticing patterns that define your unique approach to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;balance-of-power&#34;&gt;Balance of Power&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the easiest ways to define your style is by understanding your inclination toward the balance between &lt;strong&gt;power&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;territory&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 21 - The Strategy</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-21---the-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 22:21:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-21---the-strategy/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While tactics focus on local battles, strategy involves long-term planning and the overarching approach to securing victory. Developing a strong strategic mindset helps players see the board as a whole and recognize how moves in one area influence the entire game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-strategy&#34;&gt;The Importance of Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategic play ensures that every move aligns with a broader goal. Without strategy, even well-executed tactics can fail to lead to victory. Strategy in Go involves :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 20 - The Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-20---the-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 23:27:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-20---the-efficiency/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-20-the-efficiency&#34;&gt;Chapter 20: The Efficiency&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficiency is a core concept in Go that revolves around making the most of every move. In an ideal game, every stone placed should contribute to a player&amp;rsquo;s goals, whether that&amp;rsquo;s solidifying territory, attacking opponents, or reinforcing weak groups. Inefficiency wastes moves and leaves opportunities for your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficient-play&#34;&gt;Efficient Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficient moves are those that achieve maximum impact with minimal effort. To play efficiently, consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 19 - The Initiative</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-19---the-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-19---the-initiative/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, controlling the &lt;strong&gt;initiative&lt;/strong&gt;, the flow and tempo of the game, is a vital skill that separates skilled players from beginners. The concepts of &lt;strong&gt;sente&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;gote&lt;/strong&gt; form the foundation of understanding initiative. Mastering these elements helps you determine whether you&amp;rsquo;re dictating the game or responding to your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sente&#34;&gt;Sente&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A move is said to be in &lt;strong&gt;sente&lt;/strong&gt; when it forces your opponent to respond. Sente allows you to dictate the game&amp;rsquo;s flow, steering the action to areas of the board you find most advantageous. Playing in sente enables you to make progress while keeping your opponent on the defensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18 - The Capturing Race</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-18---the-capturing-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:10:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-18---the-capturing-race/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-18-the-capturing-race&#34;&gt;Chapter 18: The Capturing Race&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of Go, life and death situations often boil down to a &lt;strong&gt;capturing race&lt;/strong&gt; (semeai in japanese), where two groups compete to surround and capture each other. Mastering the capturing race is essential for determining which groups can survive and which must perish. It involves counting liberties, planning efficient moves, and understanding shared life situations like seki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-capturing-race&#34;&gt;Understanding the Capturing Race&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A capturing race occurs when at least two opposing groups of stones are locked in a struggle for survival. The winner is the group that captures the other by filling its liberties while keeping its own intact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 - The Attack and Defense</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-17---the-attack-and-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 21:34:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-17---the-attack-and-defense/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing between attack and defense can be challenging. To make the right decision, you need to focus on what’s urgent versus what’s big, and prioritize your own groups before targeting your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;urgent-vs-big-move&#34;&gt;Urgent vs Big Move&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;urgent-move&#34;&gt;Urgent Move&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urgent moves are about handling immediate threats. Even if the stakes seem small, urgent moves prevent disasters and stabilize your position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ashruidan.github.io/images/day17_urgent.png&#34; alt=&#34;day17_urgent&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, we can see that the move in A8 (triangle) is an urgent move because it decides the life and death of the Black group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - The Evaluation Skill</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-16---the-evaluation-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:29:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-16---the-evaluation-skill/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, navigating the complex situations of the midgame requires the use of your &lt;strong&gt;evaluation skill&lt;/strong&gt;. This skill involves analyzing the distribution of both territory and influence across the board. By mastering evaluation, players can assess who is leading, decide what groups or areas to attack or defend, and identify moves that can shift or maintain the balance of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;positional-judgment&#34;&gt;Positional Judgment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positional judgment&lt;/strong&gt; forms the foundation of evaluation skills. It includes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15 - The Framework</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-15---the-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 18:22:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-15---the-framework/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frameworks&lt;/strong&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;moyo&lt;/em&gt;) are large-scale structures that outline potential territory without completely enclosing it. We’ll explore the key ideas behind frameworks, including &lt;strong&gt;sector lines&lt;/strong&gt;, the difference between &lt;strong&gt;invasion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;reduction&lt;/strong&gt;, and how to navigate this exciting aspect of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sector-lines&#34;&gt;Sector Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sector lines&lt;/strong&gt; are imaginary boundaries that show the potential reach of your stones. They’re not actual walls but suggest areas where your opponent’s moves could threaten your potential territory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14 - The Influence</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-14---the-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 18:25:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-14---the-influence/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you grow in your Go journey, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that Go is not just about claiming territory outright; it&amp;rsquo;s also about creating potential. This potential often manifests as &lt;strong&gt;influence&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;thickness&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;moyo&lt;/strong&gt;, concepts that are critical to understanding deeper strategies in Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;influence&#34;&gt;Influence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the ability of your stones to control or affect a wide area of the board. Instead of focusing on immediate territory, influence lays the groundwork for future expansions or attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13 - The Shape</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-13---the-shape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 17:13:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-13---the-shape/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, shapes refer to the arrangement of stones on the board. A good shape efficiently connects stones, maximizes liberties, and prepares for future moves. A bad shape, on the other hand, is inefficient, easy to cut, or lacks flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-shapes&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good Shapes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-bamboo-joint&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Bamboo Joint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ashruidan.github.io/images/day13_bamboo.png&#34; alt=&#34;day13_bamboo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bamboo joint consists of two diagonal connections. It is uncuttable with enough liberties and provides a strong connection between stones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-the-tigers-mouth&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Tiger’s Mouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ashruidan.github.io/images/day13_tigermouth.png&#34; alt=&#34;day13_tigermouth&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12 - The Connection</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-12---the-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 18:20:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-12---the-connection/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;connection&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cutting&lt;/strong&gt; lie at the heart of the game. Connecting your stones strengthens your groups, ensuring they survive and work together. Cutting, on the other hand, aims to divide your opponent’s groups, making them weaker and creating opportunities to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connections&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting stones allows you to build strong groups and secure their survival. A well-connected group is harder to attack, provides stability, and can exert more influence on the board.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11 - The Joseki</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-11---the-joseki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:48:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-11---the-joseki/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joseki&lt;/strong&gt; are sequences of moves that are considered balanced for both sides, typically occurring in the corners. Joseki are not just fixed answers but strategic tools that depend on the overall board context. They provide a foundation for local play while influencing the global position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-common-joseki-for-beginners&#34;&gt;Five Common Joseki for Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are five joseki every beginner should know, focusing on the corner plays introduced earlier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-ai-approach-joseki&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. AI Approach Joseki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White approaches Black’s hoshi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black defends by extending at the opposite direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White fight Black for the control of the corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ashruidan.github.io/images/day11_joseki1.png&#34; alt=&#34;day11_joseki1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10 - The Basic Technique</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-10---the-basic-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:23:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-10---the-basic-technique/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go is not just about placing stones, it’s about placing them effectively. To play well, you need to understand how to you navigate the board, whether you’re building, attacking, or defending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;techniques-between-stones-of-the-same-color&#34;&gt;Techniques Between Stones of the Same Color&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When connecting or extending your stones, you have several fundamental techniques. Some are fast but fragile, slow but strong or aiming at a balance of stability and speed. These moves strengthen your position, help you claim territory, or improve your mobility :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 09 - The Opening</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-09---the-opening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:22:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-09---the-opening/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand the importance of the first moves and balancing stability and speed, it’s time to explore how these concepts come together in the opening. In this chapter, we’ll look at common corner positions, how they shape your plans, and how to extend your influence toward the sides and the center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-in-the-corner&#34;&gt;Starting in the Corner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The corner is the best starting point in Go because it provides natural boundaries for forming territory. Different common corner moves, &lt;strong&gt;hoshi (4-4)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;komoku (4-3)&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;sansan (3-3)&lt;/strong&gt;, each have unique strengths and weaknesses:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 08 - The First Moves</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-08---the-first-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 13:38:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-08---the-first-moves/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a rudimentary knowledge of the game, you may feel ready to try playing on a larger board. But a common question arises: &lt;strong&gt;Where should I place my first stones on the board, and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-play&#34;&gt;Where to Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, you can play anywhere on the board. However, if you observe experienced players, you’ll notice they often place their opening moves around the corner&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;hoshi&lt;/strong&gt; points.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 07 - The First Game</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-07---the-first-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 15:13:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-07---the-first-game/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the fundamental rules and concepts of Go, it’s time to learn how to apply them in actual gameplay. Playing against others is not just about following the rules, it’s a way to reinforce and master the skills you’ve learned so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-settings&#34;&gt;Rule Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When playing Go, several settings determine how the game is scored, how ties are resolved, and whether the game is balanced for players of different skill levels. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore these settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 06 - The Counting Skill</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-06---the-counting-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:18:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-06---the-counting-skill/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the knowledge we’ve gained, we are now equipped to understand the end of the game. The final phase is where players consolidate their territories, resolve conflicts, and prepare for the scoring phase. This is where &lt;strong&gt;counting skill&lt;/strong&gt; becomes invaluable, allowing players to determine the game’s outcome even before the board is completely settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;territory-and-the-endgame&#34;&gt;Territory and the Endgame&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, the endgame is about solidifying &lt;strong&gt;territory&lt;/strong&gt;. This means closing off any remaining gaps in your claimed areas, resolving any ongoing ko fights, and securing contested spaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 05 - The Repetition Rule</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-05---the-repetition-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:20:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-05---the-repetition-rule/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical game of Go, every move leads to a new and unique position. However, there is a special scenario where the game could fall into an endless cycle of repeated moves. To prevent this, the &lt;strong&gt;Repetition Rule&lt;/strong&gt; ensures that no position can be repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preventing-infinite-loops&#34;&gt;Preventing Infinite Loops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain situations, such as the one shown below, a player can capture a stone, only for the opponent to recapture it on the next turn, creating a loop. This would result in an endless game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 04 - The Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-04---the-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:22:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-04---the-life-and-death/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve learned how to capture, how to read sequences, and how to make life by creating two eyes. Now it’s time to delve deeper into the concept of &lt;strong&gt;life and death&lt;/strong&gt; and discover how identifying the &lt;strong&gt;vital point&lt;/strong&gt; of a group can help you save your stones or kill your opponent’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-life-and-death&#34;&gt;What is Life and Death?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, &lt;strong&gt;life and death&lt;/strong&gt; refers to whether a group of stones can survive or be captured. A group is considered alive if it can secure two eyes, while a group without sufficient space to make two eyes is doomed to die. It is critical to recognize the status of your group to get the initiative and play first the vital point to get the control into the life and death of your groups or opponent&amp;rsquo;s groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 03 - The Suicide Rule</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-03---the-suicide-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 09:44:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-03---the-suicide-rule/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Suicide Rule&lt;/strong&gt; prevents self-capturing moves and has implications for &lt;strong&gt;life and death&lt;/strong&gt; on the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-capture-as-illegal-moves&#34;&gt;Self capture as illegal Moves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Go, a player cannot place a stone on an empty intersection completely surrounded by their opponent&amp;rsquo;s stones. Such a move would leave the stone with no liberties and is considered illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ashruidan.github.io/images/day03_illegal.png&#34; alt=&#34;day03_illegal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is an exception: if the surrounding opponent&amp;rsquo;s stones are also completely surrounded by your stones, the move is allowed. This is because, in capturing the opponent&amp;rsquo;s stones, your stone regains its liberties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 02 - The Reading Skill</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-02---the-reading-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:36:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-02---the-reading-skill/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter, we explored the &lt;strong&gt;Rule of Capture&lt;/strong&gt;, learning how liberties affect the capture of stones. However, not all captures are immediately obvious. In some situations, even if you try to save a stone, the opponent can force it into atari repeatedly until it’s ultimately captured. This is where the importance of &lt;strong&gt;reading&lt;/strong&gt; begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-reading-&#34;&gt;What is Reading ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt; is the ability to visualize sequences of moves in advance. It’s a fundamental skill in Go, enabling players to foresee outcomes and make informed decisions. For example, if a capture is unavoidable, a player can choose to play elsewhere to minimize losses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 01 - The Rule of Capture</title>
      <link>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-01---the-rule-of-capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 04:20:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashruidan.github.io/posts/day-01---the-rule-of-capture/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;strong&gt;Advent of Go&lt;/strong&gt;, a 25 chapters long guide where each day is built upon the concepts of the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will not delve into the history or variations of Go, instead it will help you acquire the necessary knowledge and skills to perceive the depth of this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, Go is a two-player turn-based game where one player uses black stones and the other uses white. Black always plays first. On each turn, players can either place a stone on an empty intersection of the board or pass their turn. Once placed, a stone cannot be moved. However, stones can be removed through &lt;strong&gt;capture&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
